Well done, boys. Looks like ice-cold sushi for breakfast.
好喇呀，手足 我哟今日有冰冻毒司做早餐
No, no, son. Over here.
唔像，唔你呀，仔 !
See the lion? Look at the lion and get the lion.
瞳唔晓到和售狮子呀 ? 望实售狮子，然后攻侧 !
Now, son, if you're gonna grow up
乖仔呀，如果你第时长大…
and be like your daddy someday, you gotta learn how to fight.
想好似你答吨哇功 你就要学识点样去战站
Da-da.
移筹
Now, Alakay, let me show you something, OK?
亚拉和奇 不如等我界哟喇你虹下
You see this mark?
见到个胎记骂 ?
You and me are the same.
有其父必有其子
When you're bigger, you'll be Alpha Lion, just like me.
等你长大 你会做狮族特首，就好似我听
Now let me see you fight. Ready?
战网比答吨瞳下，得未呀?
No, Alakay. No dancing!
唔你噶样呀，哑你跳三 !
You just amuse yourself, don't you?
你党得哇榜好好玩呼 ?
You're a strange kid. You're a strange one. I'm...
真你多动静，十起猜怪
Now, come on, let's try it again.
好喝，噬多一次
No, Alakay.
唔你只样
Stop that right now. Doggone it!
停呀，即刻停呀，我叫你停 !
It's so disappointing when they don't grow up the way you want.
个仔教极都唔了 又真像北激气咯
Makunga. You're not challenging me again, are you?
猛管家 你唔像又想味挑战我喇?
Look on the bright side. After 1 defeat you and become alpha lion,
向好咽边於啦，狮区 如果我打赢吃你做狮族特首…
you'll have more time to spend with your pathetic son.
你咪可以有多哟时间 联你个低b仔唾
Before I kick your butt, let me ask you:
喉我打扁你之前 我好想问吓你…
Why do you want to become the alpha lion?
点解你哇想做狮族特首 ?
I'm better looking, ! have better hair, I'm deceivingly smart...
我样好明你 毛疯过你，仲醒目过你…
..and I want everyone else to do what I say.
…像味应该个个都了我话 !
We fight on three. One...
数三声就打啦…一…
Pay attention, Alakay. Daddy will show you how it's done.
暗住喇，亚拉奇 移吨示范点搞扩伍
Two, three!
二…三1
- Who's the alpha lion? - You are.
下个你狮族特首 ? 你你
Don't you forget it.
哇样你记住喇 !
And that, Alakay, is how you attack...
瞳到啦，亚拉奇，交像啦打…
Alakay?
亚拉奇 ?
That's it. Here, kitty, kitty.
喀哎，快哟通叶啦，猫仔
This one's a beauty.
瞳落唔错喝 !
He'll be worth a few bucks.
应该坦到好价弘
It just gets easier and easier.
扼错，易过借火呀
Daddy!
签哪 !
Alakay! Alakay!
亚拉和奇 ! 垩拉坷 !
Alakay!
亚拉奇 !
Da-da!
移移 !
No! No! No!
唔好 ! 唔好 ! 唔好呀!
Alakay!
亚拉奇 !
- Daddy! - Daddy's got you! Hold on!
签哪 ! 签吨喷救你 ! 唔使车架 !
Da-da!
移移 !
Alakay!
亚拉奇 !
Daddy!
移吨
I've been around the world in the pouring rain
《荒失失奇兵2》
- [ don't like the looks of this guy. - He's kind of cute.
我唔你好鳃意售狮子仔… 但你我党得伍疲可爱
He's kind of a showoff.
我话伍键意抢镜就真
You think he's cute?
你觉得伍可党 ?
Roar!!
暗吓!
The King of New York City...
各位，经约市之王…
...Alex the Lion!
狮子亚力 !
I still think he's kind of a showoff.
我仲你觉得 伍好任意抢镜 !
The guy's an animal.
伍真像好鬼狂野 !
Maybe he should take a break. You know, we could all use a vacation.
其实伍应该放吓假 我呈个个都订该放吓假
Come on, where would we go on vacation?
哇你话我哟去天度渡假好呢 ?
I don't know about you, but I want to go to Connecticut!
唔知你吡喝 我就想去康万迪格州!
On the loose, several animals, including the world famous Alex the Lion,
今晚中央公园动物园 走失吐北焦动物
escaped from the Central Park Zoo tonight.
其中包括经约之王狮予亚力
The escapees were cornered in Grand Central Station.
最后班动物 喉中央车站被警察包围
He was a very bad kitty.
个售猫仔真像好如
Animal rights activists, who convinced zoo officials
动物园册从动物权益人士要求
to have the animals sent to Africa,
将走失啤动物用船送返去非洲
were stunned to learn that the freighter carrying the animals
但像焦船今日居然
was reported missing today.
犯故失中
Tonight, hundreds of New Yorkers have gathered at the zoo
今晚有数以百计纽约市民 事集喉中央公园动物转
to mourn the loss of their beloved zoo animals.
哀悼一班失跑动物
The question on everyone's mind, where are they now?
大家心入面都有一个疑问 究竟伍吡去咏遵度呢 ?
I like to move it, move it
我镍意忠舞
He likes to move it, move it
他链意号舞
She likes to move it, move it
她鳃意跳大
- We like to - Move it!
我哟狂意 跳舞 !
Come on! Y'all know this one! It never gets stale!
噬呢 1 你吨都识唱架 ! 败时都嘻喘节 !
- We like to - Move it!
我哟狂意 跳舞 !
Weill miss you little fuzz buckets! You've been a great crowd!
我吨会撒住你吨班毛毛怪 ! 你吨真你一班好好吸观办呀!
Glad we could introduce you to the toilet.
好荣幸可以教识你吨用遍所
If you ever come look us up in Manhattan, feel free to call first.
如果於住去曼克顿探我吨 记得要Call我先喝
Seriously though, call. OK?
讲真架…Cal1我呀…OK?
Settle down, everybody. Be quiet!
冷静鸣，各位 聘住 !
You can't leave without this!
你界你吡嗓氏行礼物呀 !
Surprise, freaks!
车训哩，瑚哩怪 !
Shake it! Shake it.
接六 ! 的呀!
Look, I'm a lady! I'm a lady, everyone!
暗吓，我你靓女呀! 瞳岗女啦，各位…
I'm a lady! Not really! It's me, King Julien!
我你靓女，至谨呀 ! 像我，国王朱利安呀!
Which of you is attracted to me? Hands up!
头先有韶个界我迷倒呀 请淮手!
Hey, freaks! You will be very glad to hear that 1 am coming with you.
哺哩怪 ! 我决定跟理你哟走呀 点呀，你味好开心呢?
Oh, no, thank you.
唔使喇，多谢
Yes, thank you. It's my plane!
要架 ! 呢架机你我咯
Until 1 return with the spoils from the new country...
我宣饰喉我带战利品 返喀呢度之前…
... Stevie will be in charge!
呢度像由蜥蝎仔话事
I don't think they like that idea.
我诊伍哟似乎 唔像哇钙意呢个主意
What are you saying, Stevie?
你讲只话，蜥蝎仔 ?
No.
唔得
Could we...? No, you didn't say that! How is that even possible?
唔你吓话 ? 你点可以哇讲架 扼可能会哇样
Naughty little thing! Stevie says...
你真像虽虽 1 蜥蝎仔话…
Let them eat cake!
界伍地食超级撩散大蛋糕啦 !
King Julien, wait for me!
朱利安国王，等埋我呀 !
I'm all packed! I have a whole itinerary planned!
我于好行李喇 ! 我已经成个行程度好有晒喇 !
Oh, no! It's Mort! He's so annoying!
产喇 ! 你毛毛呀 ! 伍好烦架 !
Don't let him on. Stop that thing!
唔好胃伍上机 ! 阻止伍 !
He's carrying scissors and hand cream!
伍和肯定带吃指甲钳同润广霜 !
Everybody in! Quickly, get in, get in! Get in quick!
快喝上机啦 ! 上机上机 ! 上机呀!
- Struts. - Check.
支架 好 !
- Engine. Coffee maker. - Check.
引擎，咖啡机
You guys!
吗呀…
Copsie-daisy!
噢 !
That has to be the second biggest slingshot I've ever seen.
呢个都算你我见遇噬站又之中 第二大架喇
But it'll have to do. Attention.
今炎应该搞得扩啤，请注意!
This is your captain speaking.
我你你吡咯机长 !
In the event of an emergency, place the vest over your head
当遇上紧急状况啤时候 请将救生衣套落藉
then kiss your... good-bye.
然后仆…再见
New York City, here we come!
经约市，我吨唉啦 !
Pray to your personal God this hunk of junk flies.
求神拜佛史架 「咖喇] 会屎得起啦
Personal God, hunk...? What?
求…求世喇话 ?
We are go, sir.
准备好喇，Sir !
Open the door! I'm outside!
快哟开状呀，我喉外面呀 !
If cabin pressure is lost,
功一机舱气压失调
place the mask over your face to hide your terrified expression.
请戴上面音放住你个著样
Miss, aren't these supposed to be attached to my seat?
唔好意思呀小姐，呢人条喇 唔像应该秋住我张营只 ?
- No, sir. - OK, boys, launch!
唔像，先生 手足…发射 !
Launch!
发射 !
Gremlin!
妖怪呀 !
Hey, Mort.
咀，毛毛 1
Hi!
咀!
That was weird.
真你奇怪
- Somebody's dreaming. - [ think l saw Mort on the plane wing.
有人发开口欧 我好似见到毛毛吃机愤上面
You got Madagascar on the brain.
你仲像猎住马达加斯加哇
I know I'm gonna miss it.
我都好持住咽度
It was incredible. I think it'll seem more fun the further we are from it.
呢个假期真你更 我吨离咽度越让就越党得好玩
Like when you bit me on the butt?
最好玩像你咬我pat patoy 嘛
I'm gonna take that thing you're holding onto and use it onstage.
我会将呢一段你耿耿你怀上经故 用喉兽台上面
It's all part of my little actor's salad bar of emotional tidbits.
哇演员就会多哟经愿 演技至会灶火纯青
Are the butts next to the croutons?
哇你唆咏我pat pat 你今允仲唔做梗影带 ?
You don't need to be sarcastic.
你好串喝，马提 !
When we get back, I might sign up for the breeding program.
返到去之和后 或者我应该去参加配种计划
Breeding program?
配种计划 ?
We reach a point when we want to meet somebody.
我吨都你时候揭返个伴啦
Settle down, have a relationship.
即像安定落咏，投入一段关你
I can see that.
像哇架啦
What? Like dating?
吓?你话拍拖?
Yeah, dating.
像呀，拍拖 !
Other... other guys?
同其他…其他男仔 ?
What do you mean, other guys?
其他男仔?畔意思呀
What is holding up that beverage service?!
我去暗吓我哟哟饮品先 ?
I'm gonna go check.
哇耐都未嗓
You all keep talking. I'm gonna catch a few winks.
你吡慢慢倾，我想睦一睦先
It's so funny!
真你过净 !
I like laughing! It's such a nice experience!
我真像好独意笑 ! 哇样真你好 !
To laugh!
超搞笑 !
Do you mind going back? This is first class.
请你出返去，呢度像头等舱 !
It's nothing personal. We're just better than you. Maurice, I'm open! Hit me!
唔你人针对你 ! 你我哟高级明你 ! 英利斯 !喷咱1只咱!
- He shoots, he scores! - Is that Vivaldi?
百发百中 ! 像十典音乐 ?
- In-flight slave. - Can l help you, Mr. Mankiewicz?
空中难 请问有畔贵圩，遵文先生 ?
Bring my nuts on a silver platter.
用一焦银由噬碟装果仁食吓先
We were checking on our drink order.
我呈点吐哆喇饮 想虹吓站时有
Sorry. Been a little backed up.
对唔住，我而家忙紧
- l guess I'll go back... - Where's your body?
哇我都像返去… 你个身去咏遵呀?
You're freaking me out! Can you please go over there, please?
界你呆死我呀 ! 唔该你明一过噬 ?唔该晒 !
What happened to the separation of the classes?
究竟呢个世界吃险级观念 死晒去下呀?
I'm sure this democracy thing is just a fad.
民主制度只你三分甸热度
Weill go out for pineapple, my bobbly-headed boobily-boo.
我请你食荡蔓啦 我咀弹弓头傻猪猪
Skipper, look.
队长，瞳是
Analysis.
你点晓 ?
Looks like a small bulb used to indicate something unusual, like a malfunction.
联噬好似像瘟和白光灯仔 用噬警告县常状况，如机件失霆
I find it pretty and somewhat hypnotic.
我觉得都北现，仲有催上作用
That too, sir.
都像，Sir
Right! Rico?
喂!力高!
Manual!
说明韦 !
Problemo solved.
半题解决 !
- We may be out of fuel. - Why do you think so?
我员可能方油 你点解会啦认呢 ?
We've lost engine one...
一吐引擎停号…
..and engine two is no longer on fire.
而家连二号引擎都死埋火
Buckle up, boys.
坐定呀，手足 !
Don't look, doll. This might get hairy.
咪瞻呀公仔，可能会好危险
Attention! This is your captain.
请注意，我你你吡吃机长
l have good and bad news. The good news is, we're landing immediately.
有好消息同壕消息 好消息你我哟就噬降落
The bad news is, we're crash-landing.
玉消息你…像紧急降落
When it comes to air travel, we know you have no choice.
讲起坐屎机 我都知你吡根本方得后
But thanks for choosing Air Penguin.
但你都要多谢你吨后企炉航空
Raise your arms, Maurice! It's more fun when you raise your arms!
浴起手呀，英利斯 ! 哇样举晒手明净好多 !
I can fly!
我识屎喇 !
This could be it, Marty! 1 want you to know you are a one-in-a-million friend!
今炎像哇大，马提 ! 我想放你知 你像我真正啤朋友…万中藉一!
Thanks, buddy! You're the best ever!
多认呀老友 ! 你永让你最好 !
- And you won't mind when I tell you... - Tell me anything!
我估我蛮真话你唔介意呀… 你挤啦…
I broke your iPod!
我整烟咏你部iPod !
The buttons were so small! It made me mad!
哟和洗哇揭细粒! 你叫我点用嗜 !
- The horror! - I'm sorry!
有险公 ! 对唔住唾 !
- I'll kill you, butt-biter! - It was an accident!
我要表咏你 ! 咬pat怪 ! 真你意外 !
- An accident! - Butt-biter!
真你意外嗓架 ! 咬pat怪 !
I love you, Gloria! I always have!
我爱你，歌莉亚 ! 我不骂都爱 !
Like you love the beach. Or a good book. Or the beach.
好似党沙洲哇 或者一本好书，或者沙洪
Goodness, doll, you're shaking like a leaf.
你点桩呀，公仓 你成个震晒哇
Rico, you've had your fun.
力高，你玩金未呀?
Pull up.
假升
Gear down.
降落
Gently. You just want to kiss the ground.
温邓哟，好似厅吻大地哇柑
Just a peck, a smooch, like you'd kiss your sister.
细细力哇锡落去 好似锡你个妹叶柑
I said, kiss it!
我话锡伍呀!
Now just a little brake. Just a touch.
而家地轻煞尝 ! 玛郝力
I believe that's checkmate.
今光仲唔将你个军
Commence emergency landing procedure. Flaps up! Deploy!
拨动紧急降落程序 机收 ! 打开!
Oh, we're here.
到咕喇
What in the world?
做畔得亚个框架 ?
What happened to the plane? What did y‘all do to the plane?
做畔架机搞成哇 ? 你吡对架机做吐哟呼呀?
I'm OK. I'm alive.
我方事，死唔去
I can't even sleep for a minute. This is not JFK.
我只和不通你天咏一午 呢度唔像甘通迪机场
Kowalski, casualty report.
高华斯基，伤亡报告
Two passengers unaccounted for.
我哟唔见咏果个乘客
That's a number I can live with. Good landing, boys.
小数目，由得伍啦 降落得好呀，手足 !
Who says a penguin can't fly?
下个话企入唔识赤 ?
Hey, happy slappers! Is there some reason to celebrate? Look at the plane!
拍昱手呀 ? 有喇值得庆祝叭 ? 你上虹吓架屎机 !
- We'll fix it. - How are you gonna fix this?
修理到吃 用手指修理呀 ?
Grit, spit and a whole lot of duct tape.
意志、机智同埋好多胁纸
We should be up and running in, say, six to nine months.
好快伍就会飞得普 大约六到九个月
- Sixty-nine months?! - No, six to nine months.
六十九个月 ? 错…像六到九个月
Kowalski, 1 say we use this setback to our advantage.
高华斯基 我呈一定可以瑟危为机
- Where'd you get that number? - l want you to reconfigure the design.
咽六十九个月你点计出噬架 ? 你去重新修改设计
How do you estimate that?
个时间点计出噬架 ?
Pretty boy! Why don't you and your friends dig a latrine.
毅仔 ! 不如你同你班朋友 整个军匈揭吓水源啦 ?
Hold on. Who made you king of the plane wreck?
等分先 ! 焉个玩你做 了机办事人?
Excuse me? Fine. You can be in charge. You fix the plane.
唔好意思…好1! 哇你做办事人 ! 你去整慌机 !
Who gives you the authority to put me in charge?
而家关个界权你 去选我做办事人 ?
OK, then I'll remain in charge.
好啦，哇我话音事哎 !
Yeah, you will remain in charge.
好，哇你话普有晒事
You and your hippie friends stay out of our hair.
哇你就带你班嬉皮朋友走开 味阻住晒
Correcto-mundo. Because ! decided to.
唔使讲我都会 我吨而家就即刻走 !
- Good for you. - Well, this discussion isn't over.
哇就好听 好 ?9 不通呢件事仲未完 1
Higher mammals! Stay with us.
哺乳动物 ! 你吡留低
We could use your front cortexes and opposable thumbs.
可能会用得著你吡啤脑同手指
Phil! l should wash your hands out with soap.
菲力呀! 好心你唔好喉度议「粗手」啦
How in the hell-o will they fix this plane?!
你话用意志 就可以修理好架柚?
You know, grit and spit and spit.
伍话用意志、机智
A lot of spit and grit and stick-to-it-iveness.
名之伍吨会稿宾架机
That don't sound too promising.
职落唔多乐观喝
You're right. We're stuck here.
你讲得喘 ! 实走唔到喝 !
As long as we're together, we'll be OK.
最紧要就你，我号喉埋一次
Yeah, but love ain't gonna get us home.
你，但你单靠友情 像返唔到屋企另 !
Behold! The lion!
暗吓 ! 狂子呀 !
- People! - There is much to see. Moving on.
人类呀! 仲有好多喇暗，骸续行啦
Wait, wait, wait! People!
等降，等位，等阵呀 ! 人类 !
- They'll help us! - Wait up!
伍吡会才我吨 ! 等咽!
- People! Stop! - Help us!
你吨…等理呀! 划吓忙啦 !
If you stop, I'll autograph those!
你肯停，我于你吡签名 !
I know you!
我认得你!
You.
像你 !
It's the bad kitty.
呢焦猫真你旨 !
How do you like some of that?!
像咪想啦呀?
Come in, Tokyo!
收到嘛，束京 !
Right in the batteries.
一人铺清袋呀!
You think an old lady can't take care of herself?
你以为阿婆就哇好髓你嘛 ?
Next time, 1 won't go so easy on you!
下砍唔会哇容易就放明你 !
Thank you, dear.
唔该晤，观仔
Moving on!
下个景点 !
Are you out of your mind? We need help and you harass old ladies?!
你你咪痪架 ? 我哟要伍吡划手 你就走去辣愉个老太婆 ?
Out of my mind?
下个话我痪架 ?
Who's out of my mind now?
瞳吓站个将啤
- See if you can get an operator. - No problem.
频下像味真像可以打得出? 方问题
Out of my mind. We're going home.
兔允话我将六啤 我吨返屋企
Message E-4.
电讯公司
The service user has roamed outside the coverage area.
用户徐并咏漫和那服务支援吸地区
Please try again later.
请你膛哟再试遇
Am I trippin’?
像咪幻赏呀?
All those zebras... like me.
好多斑马…好似我 !
- Where are we? - San Diego.
呢度你站度 ? 台地牙忒
This time I'm 40 percent sure.
今炊我起码有四成肯定
- [ know this place. - [ think it's Africa.
我认得呢度 我估像非济
Africa?
非洲 ?
It's got to be.
背定你
Our ancestral crib.
你我吨祖宗个「实」 呀
It's in our blood. I can feel it!
血湾蕉水嘛，我feel到呀 !
No, it's more than that. It's like...
唔止像哇，呢度好似…
...déja vu, like I've been here before.
呢度似曾相识哇 我应该喷过
It's like Roots!
寻找他乡的故事 !
...déja vu, like I've been here before.
好有亲切感，我真像应该噬遇
How!
你嫌 !
Me Alex!
我…亚力!
Me and me friends fly,
我…同我朋友…科，…
fly in great metal bird.
坐住焦大织高…
Then plummet!
跟住…撞吃…
Smash ground!
抄落地 !
Go boom!
呼…鄙 1
Then here we emerge.
喷咏…呢度 !
We offer only happiness
我号…方恶意
and good greetings.
我号只像想大家有轻轻胞礁
Is he dancing about a plane crash?
伍像咪想用跳舞噬表达撞机呀?
Yeah. We just... yeah.
像呀 9 我哟喘喀…
I thought... Sorry.
我以为，对唔住 !
You came from off the reserve?
你话你吨你喉保访区外面噬 ?
Way off. From the Central Park Zoo, actually.
好速添 ! 中央公园动物园叶这呀
Don't strain yourself.
小心身体 !
What's going on here?
发生只事?
They say they're from off the reserve.
伍吡话吃保护区外面噬喝
That's impossible. Only people come from off the reserve.
方可能 只有人类先会喉保访区外面噬 !
You look familiar. Do I know you?
你好面善喝 ! 我你味识得你?
How could you survive the hunters?
你号有畔可能避明咽哟猎人 ?
We didn't see any hunters.
我哟有昂过猎人
- What are you looking at? - Me? Nothing.
你喉度望世喇? 我?有喇呀!
This watering hole doesn't need any more mouths to feed.
我呈唔要有多站把吐喉度事水饮
So skedaddle back to where you came from.
你吨由遵度叶吸就帆返去遵度
Is there a manager we could talk to?
请问呢度有有有管理员 我吨想同伍倾吓…
l see. You're here to challenge me!
我明嘲 ! 你像想叶挑战我 !
What? No! No.
吓?有…唔像 1
That's what it looks like to me!
但你我越晓越觉得似像 !
Zuba! Wait.
狮爸 ! 等了呀
I'm trying to take care of business...
男人做大事 女人就嚼好理哇多啦
Yeah, yeah, Zuba. Hold on.
狂爸，等了呀
Alakay?
亚拉奇 ?
Is that you?
你咪你呀 ?
No, it's Alex. Ix. Like New York Knicks.
唔你，我叫亚力 垩力…像大力个力
Zuba, look!
狮笃，懂下 !
I've always had that. The vet checked it out.
我一直都有呢接喇 ! 软医上虹过喘 !
It's kind of a beauty spot, really.
捷嘻只你…胎记之类，方喇肯 !
A mark.
拓胎记 !
All right, this is a little weird.
好喝 ! 而家好似怪怪地 !
Honey, he's come home.
老婆，伍返吐嗓 !
What?
吓?
You've come home.
你返咏嗓啤 !
Son.
乖仔 !
Dad.
移吨
Mom and Dad? Mom and Dad!
杂味答吨 ? 姻味签吨 !
Mom and Dad! It's my mom and dad!
嫣咪俭吨 ! 我有妈咪移吨 !
My baby's alive!
我个乖仔未死 !
Dad!
签哪 !
My son!
乖仔 !
My son is home!
我个乖仔返咏喷 !
Alakay! Alakay has come home!
亚拉和奇 ! 邓拉坷返咏屋企1
Alakay! Yeah! The prodigal son returns. This is perfect!
像垩拉奇呀! 狮爸个仔浪子回头喇 ! 好到极 !
I thought you hated Zuba.
我以为你异狂区添
No, I do. I do. I do. l hate him. Oh, I do.
我你展 ! 我懂 ! 我展! 我懂伍 ! 我好懂伍 !
And I'm going to use Alakay, yes.
所以我要利用亚拉奇，扼错
I'm going to use him to get rid of Zuba once and for all!
我要利用伍将狮区剧除 一欧永狗 !
Giddy-up, feathered horse!
快哟啦，飞天马 !
Make way! Move out of the way! Stand aside!
让并 ! 快哟让路 ! 企埋一下 !
New York!
纽约 !
It's a bit of a dump. Are you sure we're not in New Jersey?
蕊呢度哇筷 ! 你肯定呢度唔像新泽西?
Hello, New Yorkers! Your new king is here!
咀，弓约人 ! 你听新皇帝嗓喇 !
This calls for a celebration!
要庆祝一下 !
Maurice, I think they like me.
英利 斯 9 伍吡好掺访我呀
You've got to love a non-hostile takeover!
非逆意接管狗你受霓迎噬
Chukka-chukka what?
挤世话?
Excuse me. I'm Marty. I'm kind of new around here.
唔好意思，我你马提呀 我像新喷吃斑马 !
Hey, Marty!
你好吐，马提 !
You're a good-looking group! You like to run?
你吡个个都好毅仔 ! 你吡鳃唔钙意跑步?
Yeah. Running is crack-a-lackin’.
狂意，跑步简直你正到闻 !
That's right! Crack-a-lackin’.
像唾 ! 正到痊呀!
You guys speak my crack-a-lackin' language.
你吡讲明简直像同我夹到闻
What? You don't have doctors here?
吓 ?你哟呢度竟然及蜂生 ?
Not anymore.
而家扰喇 !
Well, what if you catch a cold?
啦如果你吡车到伤风呢 ?
We go over to the dying holes and we die.
我吡会去捍个窗，然后等死唾
You guys really need a doctor.
你吡真你要揭个医生
- We have an opening. - Would you be interested?
我吊招聘紧 你有方要趣 ?
Me? A doctor?
我?做医生?
It's raining men. Hallelujah! You all got it going on.
哇多仔，我真像感痊主 我终於都噬到天堂
Why don’t you have a man? You got worms?
点解你会方男朋友噬 ? 你生意呀?
Oh, I got rid of those. Listen, girls.
哆丰早就杜咏啦 ! 我话你吨知
Manhattan is short on two things, parking and hippos.
曼克顿最缺乏雨样喇 车位同河
Hey, everybody! I just found out that my son
各位 ! 我吵喘先知
is a doggone king! The King of New York!
我个仔像王者 ! 你经约之王 !
Show me some of your moves, son. Don't be bashful.
露雨招大家内吓啦 ! 乖仔
All right. This one always knocks 'em dead.
唔1我有招好欠食 !
Roar!
呵 !
Look out. The King is mad. The King is mad!
暗住呀，你皇上发火 ! 像皇上发火呀 !
Let's welcome him back into the pride with open arms!
而家我吨张并人驳手 热烈炊迎伍 !
Welcome to the herd, Marty!
斑珊群欢迎你呀 ! 马提…
Me? I've always wanted to be part of a herd!
我?了我一直想加入斑马群
- It's one for all... - [all] And all for all, y‘all!
一斑塌… 就有成斑马 ! 好喇!
How do I look?
我似唔似呀?
Technically, a traditional witch doctor has a bone through his nose.
严格噬讲 传统巫医要吃鼻度穿条骨头至得
Don't worry... it's just a clip-on.
唔使莫 1 夹上去哮
Voila! He's a witch doctor!
「 你们看」 和伍做咏巫医 !
My mother will be so happy.
我阿嫣一定会好开心 !
Look out! I think Moto Moto likes you.
暗吓 ! 我於摩图摩图好宁你
Here he comes.
伍噬紧啤 !
Goodness, girl... you huge.
只 ! 观女，你好大噶 !
Who's your friend? Or is that your butt?
呢位老友，…. 你个入机都唔细叫 ?
You as quick as you are hefty.
你头脑同四肢都发达喝
So you're Moto Moto?
你就像摩图摩图?
The name's so nice, you say it twice.
个名哇好匠，醒要多两志
I kind of like it, fatso.
我都修镍意肥佬 !
I'll see you around, girl. It won't be hard, because you so... plumpy.
我吨会再见咯 唔郊揭你哮，你叶…大份
Cops!
哎呀
l hate to be a party pooper, Zuba,
我都唔想操你哟当，狮区
but some of the lions were wondering when you plan to banish your son.
但你有哟狮子喉度咳咏吧 问你几时先放逐你个仔
- What are you talking about? - It's nothing, really.
你究竟讲紧世喇呀? 其实方世喇 !
They're griping that Alakay never went through
伍吡个个都话垩拉和奇
the rite of passage, blah, blah, blah,
从来及通过考验仪式 诸如此类啦
so technically speaking, he can't be a member of the pride. It's nonsense.
所以严格唉讲 伍唔像狮群肯一份子，乱讲哮 !
I forgot about the rite of passage.
我真你唔记得咏考验仪式添
What is it? What's this rite of passage?
畔架 ? 昱考验仪式呀?
A traditional coming-of-age ceremony.
你代表成年啤传统仪式
Young lions earn their manes by demonstrating their skills.
像象徽幼狮长出捅毛 要向大家展示技能
- A show-of-skill talent show deal? - Yeah. Strutting their stuff.
即像天才表演哇上下啦 ? 你呀 ! 双吓Quali吧 !
A performance! I think that's up my alley.
表演机会 ! 开正我咽辩 !
If it's tradition, 1 want to do it. Strut my stuff. Earn my mane.
既然你传统，我就照做啦 ! 骚吓Quali ! 演吓始毛 !
I want to be Alaki.
我要做普亚拉蕉
- Alakay. - Alakay! Even better.
像垩拉奇呀! 亚拉和奇 ! 哇叫仲好双 !
We will hold the rite of passage in the morning!
我喇节朝一早就举行考验仪式!
That's wonderful! Good luck, Alakay.
哇至像嘛 ! 祝你好带
Where I'm from, we say, "Break a leg."
我唔使运气都会大杀四方 !
That's my boy!
哇样至你我咕乖仔 !
I'm a private dancer
我你个私人手者
A dancer for money
贪钱的舞者
Any old music will do
任何著歌都可以
Beautiful, isn't it?
好毅，你咪 ?
It's amazing.
真你好疯呀!
.. this is where we belong.
我吨属僚呢度
Operation Tourist Trap is a go.
「 诱捕闭客行动」 准备好 !
Oh, I like that one.
呢个名改得好 !
It works on many levels.
仲可以有效种解释添
You guys are a bunch of suck-ups.
你吡成班都你探鞋仔
- That, too. - Absolutely.
像听 讲得喘 !
Stations.
各就各位
Stage one. Go!
第一步! 上!
Oh, no! What have I done?
惨啦 ! 我做吐畔事?
Come on, take the bait.
叱吨…上的喇 !
- What happened? - Oh, look at the poor little guy.
发生只事? 暗吓呢个可展啤小信伙
Is it dead?
伍死吐?
Stage two! Go, go, go!
第二步1上1上1上1!
I will give him the kiss of life.
不如就等我锡返生伍啦 !
Rico!
力高!
Reverse!
倒和后 !
Gas!
油门 !
Music!
音乐 !
No! Stop! Stop!
惨 ! 停呀! 停呀!
Stop!
停呀 !
Come back!
返喉呀!
What is all this rock'n'roll racket?!
做叭播拘滚乐嘲生晒呀?
Is she dead?
死吐啤 ?
No!
未 !
You hoodlums!
死飞仔 !
Good heavens! Are you OK?
除公咯 ! 你方事嘛 ?
Lady, I found your pocketbook.
阿焉…我揭到你个手袋
My handbag. Such a good boy.
我个手袋 ! 你真你竹仔 !
Nana can't survive without it.
娘娘唔可以方吐伍 !
You are one tough cookie.
你都修老而红坚喝 !
Brownies Troop 416, Yonkers.
我像曼克顿2416队女童军
OK, nobody panic! The best thing we can do is stay together.
明白，大家唔使车 ! 只要国埋一就会有事
Weill wait for another tour jeep. It may take hours, but...
我哟喉度等下一架观光车 路然可能等站个甸…
Where are you going?
你去下度呀 ?
I'm not staying here to be attacked by more animals! I'm too old to die.
我唔会留嘛空蜡地方等动物亲测 我喇老唔可以死听
I'm going with her. Old lady, wait up!
我就哑知你吨点认，我就跟醒伍 阿焉 ! 等埋呀 !
Please! We need to stay...
各位 ! 我号要一变…
...together.
唔可以走散
Fine! We'll go that way!
好 ! 哇行咽亲啦 !
Does anyone want a hard candy?
你员有方人想食糖 ?
- Easy now. - Watch your step.
小 心哟 好声行
And right here... OK, are you ready?
像呢度喇…好喇，淮人备好未?
This is where you always slept.
呢度就像你以前避吸地方
Oh, man!
噢，正呀!
- Was this mine? - Look at you. Look at him.
像我吸 ? 暗吓你 ! 虹吓全
Oh, this thing. Look, look!
呢样咯 ! 频吓!瞳吓!
- l remember this! - He remembers.
我记得呀! 伍记得
A little harder than...
原来哇硬架…
You never slept on the right end. You always slept on the bottom end.
你成日锡啦反剖! 烟居到碌落地
Is that...?
呢.个…
Is that my...?
呢个像… ?
Is that me?
我整呀?
You had the cutest little paws.
你售爪他你最得意啤
Little, little bitty ol' paws.
不仔、不他、的蜗不个
You did that the day we lost you.
像你失跑咽日留会听
Wow. I was so young.
哗，我咽阵好细
What happened to me?
发生吐只事呢?
It was all my fault. I turned my back and...
呢个你我吸错 ! 我只你摔圭头一分甸就…
It was not your fault.
根本唔像你啤错
Your father did everything he could. He tracked those hunters for weeks.
你移员已经驯晒力喇 伍追咏哟猎人好北个礼拜
Far off the reserve.
谁保护区好速
Finally, had to assume the hunters...
最后我以为咽哟猎人将你…
.. well...
o五.- 吾
We thought they'd killed you.
我吨以为伍吨共咏你
But my son fought them off! Don’t mess with the King of New York!
不过我个仔搞扩吐哟猎人 ! 经约之王唔好惹上 !
- That's right! - Keep your chin in.
有有错呀 ! 缩埋下上爬
You boys be careful! Watch out before you break something.
你吡小心顺 ! 你噶住唔好打烟哟嘻 !
You used to call this "foofie."
你以前叫伍做「菲菲]
"Foofie"?
菲菲?
Foofie.
菲菲呀!
He doesn't want that.
伍已经唔要呢哟电
This is my foofie!
唔好抢我菲菲 !
Zuba, you better give him his foofie.
狮笃，唾好搞伍个菲菲
I mean, no, thank you, thank you. It's perfect.
我想话，多谢…多洽 ! 太好喇
Son, you get your rest. You have a big day tomorrow.
冬仔你休息吓 ! 匠日就你你咕大日子
You'll need all your strength.
你要疼精著铝 !
I will bring the house down for you.
我匠日一定会威界你暗嗓釜吡
l hope so. Otherwise, your father will have to banish you.
希望啦 如果唔你你移吨会放逐你
Jeez, Mom, really?
吓，讲真?
I know you'll do us proud. You know why?
我知道你一定会令到我吡自各听 知道点解骂 ?
You were born with it.
因为你天生有才能
Good night, Alakay.
早样，亚拉奇
My boy. My own boy.
乖仔，我个乖仔 !
My son's a king.
我个仔像王者
Good night, Mom.
早样，嫣咪
Good night, Alakay.
早拌，亚拉奇…
Foofie.
菲菲
Look at foofie! My foofie!
你上虹吓我菲菲 ! 我吸菲菲!
Foofie, foofie, foofie. My foofie!
我个菲菲 ! 菲菲 ! 菲菲!
No sign of civilization. Everybody appears very tired.
一哟文明踊象都有 个个都妇到死 !
I think we're lost.
我於我哟落失路
Nana, do you know where you're going?
娘娘，你知唔知你去紧遵 ?
No, but I'm going with a skip in my step and a smile on my face.
唔知，但你我会见步行步 然后笑住上路
Sure, right, OK. Yeah, all right.
吵，好咱 ! 喘咱，好呀
- It's people. - How did you get here?
有人呀! 你吨点噬架 ?
- Can you help us? We're lost. - We're lost too.
救吓我呈，我员落失路 我吡都像呀
It was awful. A flash of black and white and they were gone. They took the jeep!
好恐怖 ! 突然黑白色一内 就变成啦喇 ! 伍哟的吐架车 !
- That happened to our jeep too! - What do we do?
我吡架车都你哇呀 哇我吨点算好 ?
How will we all survive?
我号吃度吕生存 ?
No food, no water, no shelter. What are we gonna do?!
有食物，有水饮，又方瓦放头 我吨点算 ?
You can let nature get the best of you,
你可以胃》大自然征服你
or you can get the best of nature.
亦都一样可以征服到大自然!
Gather ‘round, children. We're New Yorkers, right?
围理吧啦细路 我吨你经约人，你咪 ?
Yeah.
像咱
We survive the concrete jungle!
我吨征服到石尿森林
When we need food, we hunt for a decent hot dog stand.
我吨要食物吃话 就会揭到热狗档
- Am I right? - She's right.
像咪 ? 伍讲得喘
When we need shelter, we build skyscrapers.
要瓦遮里，就起摩天大麻
- Exactly! - When we need water, we build a dam.
有有错! 要伺水肯话，我哟就去起堤填
We're New Yorkers, for crying out loud!
我员像弓约人人，大志叫啦 !
If we can make it there,
叭经约都截到的士
we can make it anywhere!
把论去到尊度都揭到车坐 !
I'm coming, King Julien!
我噬啦，朱利安国王 !
Bad fishy! Bad fishy!
慢旨和急 上费旨重 !
No, shark, no! Sit!
惨，汶和鳃1!唔好!坐!
Why am I laughing?
我笑昱呢?
We have all the parts we need, but we're slightly behind schedule.
队长，我吨揭这零件喇 不遇进度延误吐些少
- How slightly? - Six to nine years.
点些少法呀? 六至九年
- Sixty-nine years? - No, six to nine years.
六十九年? 错，你六至九年
Private! What happened to our thumbs?
卒仔 ! 我哟哟手指喉亲呀 ?
Haven't seen them since yesterday.
咱日之和后方见通呈
Darn you, Darwin!
最训达霄文 !
Nobody goes AWOL on my watch. Private! You're coming with me.
我肯属下唔可以有逃兵 ! 雁仔 ! 你跟我味 !
Rico! You're coming with me!
力高，你都跟我噬 !
- We'll bring them in for court martial. - That won't be necessary!
我吨要提伍哟上军事法庭 似乎有哇吃需要 !
We've recruited a few extra thumbs for you, Skipper.
我哩只不过像去 招幕多哟手指哮，队长
Well, I'll be a monkey's uncle.
你播撮毛出吃变架 ?
Oh, ! doubt that.
我录有哇多毛
Enough lollygagging. Let's get to work.
咪咳叶咯咱喇，去开工哎 !
There'll be three groups. Group Alpha will do sheet metal fabrication.
我吨而家分成三组 艾法组负责抽造钢板
Group Bronson handles assembly. Group George Peppard, craft services.
布朗臣组负责装蔡 佐治柏巴德组负责场务
Any questions?
有方问题 ?
Good! Let's get to work.
好!哇而家开工啦
I'd like to kiss you, monkey man.
真你想锡你一唉，马驳仔
All right, but you're so darn ugly.
好啦，不过你好梗柑
Remember, little cub scouts, a great dance performance comes from the heart.
匠住，各位狂弟 记住出色噬磊蹈表现要发自内心
Straight from the heart, you'll never go wrong.
只要做到由心出发 哇就实有衰上
Sure, mister.
知道喇，先生
Hey, Alakay, I just happened to walk by, I thought I'd wish you luck.
喂，亚拉奇 我晨喘经过认住祝你好到
- You're not nervous, are you? - Nah, it's my thing.
你有方党得紧张呀 ? 有及，好鬼淡定 ! 呢榜你我强项
In my opinion, the key to this is choosing the right competitor.
计我话呢，如果你要过天 最紧要就你识得后对手
You mean, this is like a dance battle sort of thing?
你像益，呢个仪式 只你一场基艺比试?
- Like a dance-off? - Sure.
一对一决战 ? 像 !
Great. I love that. Freestyle.
好，我钙意呀 ! 自由发挥
Who'd be a good match for me? Just to keep things interesting.
你话还个最喘做我对手呢 等场面刺激哟嘛
Well, l wish I could help,
我都想草你
but that's strictly against our ancient tradition and all we hold sacred.
不过我吡啤传统神杜不可便犯 我唔可以哇做
But if it was me out there... I'd choose Teetsi.
但像如果你我… 我会后玉芝
Teetsi. OK. Sounds interesting.
玉芝…好呀 ! 匠落应该效得意
Makunga, right? Thank you.
猛管家，你嘛?唔该晒
Anything for Zuba's boy. Go get 'em, tiger.
我醒草狮爸个仔吃 ! 你诺赢架 !
Shake it out.
嗓呈喂 !
A five, six, seven, eight.
5、6、7、8
Let's go, let's do this.
上啦，喀噶，开始啦 !
Let us begin the rite of passage ceremony.
成年考验仪式而家正式开始 !
- Come on, baby! Make Mama proud! - Woman, I'm trying to take...
去哆，裤上贝仔 ! 等杂咪威吓 ! 唉，女人，我喉度做紧正经事
On it, Mom!
得蔷，妈咪 !
Who will be the first participant?
亲人咎你第一个参加者 ?
Me! Oh! Me, me, me! Me! Me! Me! Me, me! Please, me?
我1!喂1我呀! 我1我1后我啦 !唔该 !
How about you? The tall, handsome one.
就后你啦，高大英俊咽位
Yeah. Choose your opponent.
像，你后对手啦
Let me see.
暗吓先
I guess I'll pick...
我决定擅…
... Teetsi?
玉芝
Teetsi? Why did he pick Teetsi?
救艺?点解伍会后玉芝 ?
That's my boy! He's got some gumption there!
果然你我个仔 ! 有画啦上下脆识!
Somebody, wake him up!
快哟去，叫醒伍 !
All right, so, Teetsi, come on. Let's do this, huh?
好啦 !喂玫芝，喉哟! 得未呀，吓?
Come on, little tsetse fly. Let's see your stuff. Bring it.
喷哎，玉芝仔! 暗吓你有畔料到…叶啦
- Let's dance! - OK.
浅武啦 ! 好呀
But let me warn you that lam a protégé of...
咪话我有事先警告你 我曾经赢过…
...Fosse and Robbins!
「 百老匿动兽王」 !
Not "dance" dance! Fight!
唔你跳兽…像比武 !
Dance fight! You got it.
比舞邯 ! 方问题
- ls he dancing? - What's he doing?
伍跳紧兽 ? 伍做世喇呀?
I know that boy is not dancing.
我估伍唔像跳舞叶 ?
This is even better than I thought.
早知伍你哇我就喇使伤脑和范 !
Alakay, turn around!
型拉奇…转身呀!
No, Pop, it's hop, shuffle, ball change, hip swish, turn around.
错啦，移 ! 要跳起、碎步 塌重心、完成花式，先至转身
Oh, no.
唔像嘛 !
Alakay! Are you hurt?
型拉奇，你有事咱骂 ?
Yeah, l am.
我真你好痛呀 !
Did I... did l win?
哇我…有方赢呀?
No, son.
仔呀…你瑜吐 !
How could this happen?
点会发生哇吃事 ?
You told us you were a king. A king does not get beat.
又话你你一个王者 王者又点解会输?
lam a king. I'm the King of New York.
我你王者，我你垦约之王
It's my stage name. Like for when I perform.
其实呢个你我蔓名 即你表演用肯名呀!
Perform?
表演 ?
Oh, no, this is horrible! Alakay has failed the test!
噢，惨喇，方除公 ! 亚拉奇通唔过考验 !
Who would have ever imagined that today Zuba would have to banish...
有站个会估到今日 狮区要亲手放逐…
..his own son?
伍个仔 ?
Zuba, no.
狮笃，唾好 !
Zuba, yes.
狮和区，你!
Sadly, the alpha lion must cast out all failures.
既然你像狮族特首 就一定唔可以徇私
Then I'm no longer the alpha lion.
哇我情顾喇再做狮族特首
Dad, what are you doing?
移吨，你做只呀?
Dad, no! You can't do this.
签吨 ! 唔好呀，你唔可以哇架 !
Who could possibly take Zuba's place?
哇究竟站个接替狮公好呢 ?
Anyone?
自项啦 ?
Someone? No one?
有方呀?真像方 ?
You, sir!
就膛你 !
I guess not.
广可能 !
Well, I... this is all very awkward,
呀，我…哇讲好似唔多爱
but I suppose I could carry this tremendous burden.
但估只有我至措得起呢个重据
Teetsi! Get the hat.
玉芝 ! 擒顶帐噬
As your new leader, l hereby banish Alakay!
作为新领袖 我宣饰放逐亚拉坷 !
He shall wear this Hat of Shame...
我要伍永速戴住呢顶职厚之惕…
..and leave the watering hole
区并一千年…
for a thousand years, or life!
或者一世!
Whichever comes last.
以谤长者为准
Shoo, shoo! Get out of here!
扯…扯呀 ! 快哟走开 !
You should have told us you weren't a real king, son!
仔 ! 你应该一早讲清楚 你唔像真正王者
You never told me I'd have to fight anybody!
你久方话佛我知我要去打交啦 !
What did you expect?!
你想我点样呀仔 ?
I don't know! Maybe a little fatherly advice like, "Hey, son, it's a fight!"
我唔知，或者起码同我讲句… 喂1!仔呀，你要打交 !
- You're a lion! - But I never fought another lion!
你像狮子 ! 但我成世方同其他狮子打通交 !
No, I guess not. You dance!
你方，你泽你喉度跳狂 !
And other stuff! Your pal, Makunga, set me up back there!
仲有呀 ! 你你咽个老友猛管家 伍陷害我呀 !
- None of this would have happened... - If you were a real lion.
原本都唔会搞成听，最衰… 最豪你方狮子气慨 !
- Zuba! - Yeah, I said it!
狮区 ! 像，我你哇讲 !
A real lion.
狮子气慨 !
Thanks.
多谢 !
Thanks a lot.
多谢晒 !
Suture.
人针线…
Swab.
抹汗
You're in my light, Stephen.
你遮住我，史提芬
You have a brown spot on your shoulder.
你脖头咽度好似有搂啡色喇喝
That's very observant, Stephen. As you can see, I'm covered in brown spots.
蕊你哇好眼上，史提芬 你都见啦，我全身都有啡点 !
OK! That bone will be good as new in a few weeks.
等站个礼拜吹骨就会好各
So I don't have to pick out a dying hole?
即你我唔使捍个窗咯等死?
No, you got your whole life ahead of you.
唔使，你前面仲有大把日子过 !
- Really? - Go out and grab it by the horns.
真咱 ? 出著去，勇敢哟生活啦
- Thank you, Dr. Mankiewicz! - Break a leg! Sweet kid.
多认你，遵文医生 ! 唔使客气，真你精震
This spot looks like Witch Doctor's Disease.
呢接喇似你巫医症候群虽
Witch Doctor's Disease? That's the most ridiculous disease I've ever heard of.
你话巫医症候群 ? 我从来都有台明哟哇荒谓啤病
- Don't ask. - Someone's been knotty.
唔好间 做只哇慢提呀
This won't hurt a bit.
唔会痛吃
Joe, our last witch doctor, had a spot just like that.
阿祖呢，我呈上一个和巫医 伍都有拉叶嘎叫…
- And? - Monday, Joe. Wednesday, no Joe.
…哇呢.? 星期一阿祖仲喉度，星期三方咏
Wednesday, no Joe?
星期三有咏阿祖 ?
l can breathe! Thanks, doc!
我抖到气啦 ! 多府医生 !
So this Witch Doctor's Disease is a real thing?
哇即像疼巫医症候群 你真有其事 ?
You'll find a cure. You've got at least 48 hours!
揭到药医噬 ! 你仲有四十八个伪哇多 !
But I've never heard of it.
但你我从来都方孤遇呢个病
I mean... 1 don’t have any penicillin.
你知啦…呢度又有盘尼西林 !
I'll need a CAT scan just to get started!
如果要查呢个病因 首先一定要栓身
Have a lion look you over. They'd be happy to.
可以揭狂子幕吓你 伍吡哇鳃意
Ta-dal!!
好喇嘲 !
- He has talent. - Stupendous and tremendous.
伍都效扩喝 ! 锡旺姿款、锡果实际
Hollah!
水勾失礼 !
Bet you've never seen that one! Knocked 'em dead in New York!
我於你吡一定未见明呢招 ! 风靡成个弓约呀
- Let's all give it a try! - Let's do it!
大家一亦试吓 ! 一诸做啦 !
Well, you can try all you want to,
要试就即管试
but it takes years of practice.
不过唔像哇容易 要张好多年
You'll never get a tight stream
先至喷到哟哇动吸水柱
until you build up your lip muscles to the point where you can
首先要张到口唇咯肌肉
purse your lips like this. You got it?
可以吸到个茧好似对润肠叶 ! 明白未?
Ta-da!
好喇嘲 !
How did you...? You guys got it right out of the box!
点解会… ? 你哟点会吸一融做到架 ?
- If you can do it... - ...we can do it.
你做到吃 我吨都做到
It's in our blood!
血溃藉水嘛 !
l always thought I was a bit unique.
等我仲以为我好独特添
We are unique!
我吨好独特 !
We are like a force of nature!
我吨就你大自然肯力量 !
- A million points of light! - And dark stripes!
一百苗粒流星 ! 同黑色间人条 !
Exactly the same!
全部都一样 !
Exactly the same.
全部都一样
Looks impressive, Kowalski, but will it fly?
频落唔错 高华斯基，不遇伍飞得起叭 ?
Yes. If we fold it here, here and here.
得，只要哇柑揭，再扫…再提
Nice.
扩
Oh, man. My dad thinks I'm a total loser.
老友，我移哟认篇我有用 !
I've ruined my parents’ lives.
我今欢达累咏我妈咪移吨
That is definitely not crack-a-lackin’.
哇就真你唔你正到玖 像惨明死 !
It is lackin' in the crackin’, my friend. I've gotta fix this.
直情就像死得惨啦，老友 我一定要搞普扩伍 !
So...
像喇…
.. there's... There's something I gotta tell you.
我有哟喇想同你号请
Is this place great or what?!
呢度真像好楼拖
Well, I'll tell you what. You're not gonna believe it, but...
我话你哟知 你吨可能唔信，但你…
...[ got a date with Moto Moto.
我约咏摩图摩图拍拖呀 !
Who's Moto Moto?
亲人咎你摩图摩图?
Oh, he's so big and handsome and big!
伍又大售又英俊…又大焦 !
- Know what "Moto Moto" means? - Twins?
知唔知 [摩图摩图」 点解? 了行仔?
It means, "Hot Hot."
即像「巧热巧热]
“Hot Hot"?
「 巧热巧热」 ?
When did you start parlez-ing African?
你几时学识非洲母语架 ?
It's in my blood.
血湾藉水嘛
Don't worry, you can flirt around with Mr. Hot Pants after I'm gone.
唔使莫，我行并吃 你咪可以同热裤先生依泣唆
Melman, why am I the parade and you're the rain?
做畔事呀，遵文 ? 我要去打波，你先走嗓落两?
Why are you driving your parade under my rain?
哇点解落紧雨你又走噬打波 ?
Maybe I'll parade in another part of town!
哇我最多咪去 呢个镇上另一下打波唾 !
Whoa, guys.
老友 !
Main Street's mine!
你最好走咏就唔好返喷揭我 !
Well, you can have it!
好，你自己一个人 留喉非洲发霉啦
And you can take your hotee-tot float and Mr. Hotee Moto Moto...
你鱼意就去玩你咽个生热于肥波 仲有你个老土啤摩图摩图…
- What are you talking about? - What are we talking about?
你话畔生热至 ? 你讲昱喇呀… 我哟讲紧只呀?
Melman, just tell her.
不如你坦白话伟伍知啦 ?
What? What are you... I don't know what you're talking about.
畔呀? 你请叭呀… 我都唔知你喻也 !
I guess I'll go, then.
我诊我都像走喇 !
Don't bother.
好呼，你啦你走啦 !
- Don't get up on my account. - Melman! Gloria!
同你方偶倾 ! 邀文 ! 歌痢亚 !
- [thought you guys were friends! - Marty's absolutely right.
我仲以为你吨像老友添 ! 其实马提训得好喘 !
- Marty?
马提?
What the heck is going on?
发生蕊喇事?
You're not...? Oh! He was... I thought he... You're not him. He's... Oh.
你唔像…?噢1伍你…我以为… 你唔像伍 ! 伍至像…哎呈 !
.. was me?
像我?
No. I mean, yes, you... Guys, come on.
唔像 1 好喇 ! 我认…像! 你哟个赚真像…
You thought I was him?
你当我你伍?
You guys kind of do look a little...
你吡上晓落真你有哟…
You look a lot alike. Marty, you look a lot alike.
直情一模一样 ! 马提，你哟成个饼印哇
You laugh alike. Talk alike. He has the same speech pattern.
笑容一样，讲喇一样 伍讲嘻吃语气同你似到十足
It's a little weird, really. I mean, come on. Marty.
一晨认错你唔怪得我呀，马提
So you're saying there's nothing unique about me.
你即像族我哟嗓特别都方 !
I'm just like any other zebra.
即你同其他斑马一样 ?
No. Of course you're different!
唔会，点会…你好唔同 !
How?
例如呢…
OK, I can't tell you apart.
好啦 ! 我分唔出你吨 !
Maybe you could wear a bell or something.
或者你戴个哪哪唾
- A bell?! - OK, not a bell. Bell's a bad idea.
哪哪? 唔戴哪哪 ! 哪哪唔你好主意 !
How about a T-shirt that says, "I'm with stupid"?
不如著件T恤 印住 [我隔入你傻仔1 咱? 1
- I'm not stupid! - Not you, stupid! Him, stupid!
我唔你傻仔 ! 唔你你呀…俐和仔 ! 伍呀 ! 傻仔 !
You know, while you've been doing the prancing pony with your new posse,
当你同你咽班下他 喉度玩紧跑马仔咽障
I've been having the worst day of my life.
我成世最痛苦吃一日
It's always about you, isn't it?
你又你顾住自己，你咪呼 ?
My problems are just a little bit bigger than yours.
我只不通话 我听烦民大遇你嗜，马提 !
I couldn't tell you apart. So what?!
方错我像分唔到你哟 哇又点 ?
Yeah, fine. Run away, Marty! Run away!
好昱，走叫马提 !走叫!
That's what you do best! Just like back in New York!
你最肋就走吐去架啦 ! 好似像经约咽午哇 !
I'm right here. But you can't tell that, right?
我仲吃度呀! 不明你分唔到之嘛…
Your one-of-a-million friend hopes you enjoy
我只你你菌中之一嘎朋友
your bigger-than-anyone-else's problems alone!
你个烦蚁大成哮 哇你自己搞扩伍啦 !
Good, leave! I don't need you to help me solve my problems!
好 !走啦 ! 我根本就哑使你 草我解决我听烦恪 !
You're a dime a dozen! I can't tell which one's Marty!
你像十政店货仔! 我分唔出下个你马提 !
Which one's Marty? Wait a minute. Oh, yeah, I don't care!
下个马提呀 ? 提呢… 算数，话知你呀 !
Nice hat, you showoff!
毅幅喝，抢晒镜啦 !
...don't go.
唔好走啦
Giddy-up, giddy-up!
快哟啦 ! 快哟啦 !
Look, Maurice!
暗吓，英利斯 !
The perfect spot for my summer palace!
呢度最虽起个宫殿嗓避时 !
Please fill in all these holes and relocate the riff-raff.
即刻填晒呢哟窗 然合安置班烟匈
- Who'd leave a perfectly good head? - What a waste.
焉个漏低吐个叶好吸头喉度 ? 真你叭喇 !
Tell me about it. I'm in my prime here.
你讲得喘呀，我仲叶年青力由
I'm terminal, you know?
哇就玩完，除公哦 ?
I probably only have another two days left to live.
断估可以仲有了十日命叶上下呼
That's a bummer, man.
真你晴天露震
lf l, King Julien... that's my name...
如果我，沸晶大名咱… 朱利安国王…
..only had two days left to live,
只你泽返十日命
l would do all the things
我一定会做
- I've ever dreamed of doing. - Like what?
我葛宁以求吸事 ! 例如兄?
I'd love to become a professional whistler.
我一直以嗓 都好想成为职业吹口哨专家
I'm pretty amazing at it now, but I want to get even better,
我而家都吹得两哎架 但你我想做到精益求精
make my living out of it.
希望可以车吹揭食!
You know what else I would do? l would invade a neighboring country
知唔知我仲想做昱 ? 我要侵略郑近啤国家
and impose my own ideology, even if they didn't want it!
仲要将我自己肯意识形念 来硬加只人吡身上 !
Easy for you to say. You're a king.
你像国王梗像口稀
Yes. And you are only just a sad little head.
喀 1! 路然你只不过你一个 可展上咯傻头 !
There must be something you want to do before you die!
不明你死之前 恕有哟喇你想做哇
- There is this one thing. - What? Tell me.
你有一样喇 做昱呀? 讲我知听
- No, I couldn't. - What is it?
唔得，唔讲得 你只哮 ?
I never told Gloria how I feel about her.
我对歌痢亚好有感觉 但你方脆表和白
What is it? Please tell me!
昱感觉?话我知哎…唔该 !
l never had the guts to tell Gloria how I feel about her.
我一直方脆量及勇气 向歌莉亚表和白我吸感党
How I've always felt about her.
像多年味咯感觉
Fine. Don't tell me!
得喇 ! 我明啦 !
Is ita woman? You didn't tell me it's a woman.
你讲紧女仔 ! 唔使讲我都知你讲紧女仔
What are you afraid of? You're a dead man anyway.
你担心哟叭 ? 你你咪都死架哎 ! 去啦 !
Yeah. Yeah.
像，人条
You're right.
你讲得喘
You've got to march right up to this woman.
你要街去咽个女仔面前
Look her right in the eye. Lean forward.
记得望实伍对了眼 然后倾前个身
Just a little, or almost all the way.
少少哟或者挨晒埋去
Then you let her lean forward a little until you're...
跟住就等伍轻轻叶 挨理嗓你咽度直到你…
.. just lips' distance away from each other.
个噶差哟撼到伍个嘴咽了
Then you tell her how much you hate her.
然后你就话伍知你有北哇惜伍
Actually, it's more like love her.
其实我像想讲爱伍!
Oh, you sly dog! Woof, woof!
哇，你呢焦奸狗 !
You're a real player. Now listen to me.
估唔到你你一个大情于 你而家婴我讲!
You got to rise up. You hearing me?
你要即刻企出吃 ! 匠到未呀 ?
- He didn't hear you. - l can't hear you!
伍匠唔到你讲世 ! 我孤唔到喝 !
- You got to rise up! - Rising up!
你而家企起身 ! 企起身…
- Get out of the hole! - I'm rising out of the ground!
你要即刻疮并呢一个条仔 ! 我要企返上地面 !
- He's rising, Maurice. - I'm rising, Maurice!
伍出噬喇，英利斯 我出喷喇，莫利斯
- Rising! - You go right up to this woman!
企起身… 你要即刻出去揭咽个女仔 !
Do you feel it?
有方感党?
- Go up to her face! - Tell the truth!
即刻走到去伍面前 ! 兹出真相 !
- I'm going to tell her! - Then you say, "Baby, I dig you!"
我要话伍知 ! 你要同伍讲「裤贝，我爱你1 1
Yeah! I'm going to do it! I'm going to do it!
像 ! 我要去 ! 我一定要去 !
I love that happy little head.
伍真像个开心死人头 !
She love
伍党我
Moto Moto
摩图摩图
She loves me She loves my eyes
党我对了眼
She loves my thighs
伍党我 爱我对脾
She loves my roundness
党我圆揉探
She love that I'm chunky She love that I'm plumpy
伍爱我约大份 伍党我县下下
She love my heftiness She love my zestiness
伍爱我肥嘟嘟 伍党我风趣幽默
She love me restlessly She love me forever
伍不停哇爱我 伍爱我到永速
She love me...
伍党我…
...'cause she love me
因为伍爱我
...before things get too serious, well,
趁我号未正式开始
l was wondering, if l were to, for example, stay here...
我叭度认如果我 留低喉度吃话…
.I'd like to ask you...
我想闫吓你…
Let your candied lips be the messengers to my... ear canal.
让你的朱层按摩 按摩我的…耳谭
l have so many questions.
其实我有好多喇想问
I promise the answer will always be yes.
我保证狗之你问只我都答好
Unless no is required.
除非你想要我答No
So what is it about me that you find so interesting?
叶你话我知 其实你欣赏我哟世喇?
You're the most plumpenest girl I've ever met.
你喉我见明最肥嘲嘲吃女仔
OK. Other than that.
好，仲有呢 ?
Yeah, well, you know... you chunky.
你呀…你圆太碌
Right.
像
My gosh, girl, you huge.
仲有，你好大焦
You said that.
你谐咏喇 !
Yeah, that's right.
听，像喝
We don't have to talk no more.
哇唔使再讲啦 !
Gloria!
歌痢亚 !
Gloria.
歌莉亚
Melman.
遵文
Melman, I want you to meet Moto Moto.
遵文，我想介绍你识摩图摩图
Moto Moto. Yeah, nice to meet you.
摩图摩图，广会
- l guess I... - It's OK, Melman.
得嘱，闹文
Apology accepted.
我接受你啤道歉
Oh. Yeah, right, that. That's why I... Good.
哦，哇就好喇 哇就你呀…太好喇
OK. Well, that's it, then.
方间题…你噶我就走先喇
Good. We're kind of busy here, man.
好呀，我吨都忙紧
No. No, that's not it.
唔得，唔得，哇你唔得架
Listen, Mototo, you better treat this lady like a queen.
台住，摩图图 一定要当呢位女士像王后
Because you, my friend, you found yourself the perfect woman.
因为你揭到个十全十美吸女仔
If was ever so lucky to find the perfect woman,
揭到个完美吃女仔
I'd give her flowers every day. And not just any flowers. OK?
我每日都会送花界全 伍唔你畔花都钙意架，匠住…
Her favorites are orchids. White. And breakfast in bed.
伍最键意啤你震花 白兰，仲要喉床上食早餐
Six loaves of wheat toast, butter on both sides.
六声礁包多士 雨站夺牛油
No crust, the way she likes it.
和飞天，伍就最链意
I'd be her shoulder to cry on and her best friend.
我会借个肚头界伍喊 做伍最好吃朋友
I'd spend every day thinking of how to make her laugh.
扼论北辛苦 日日我都会想怠办法去您伍笑
She has the most amazing laugh.
因为只有伍拉有 最爽朗吸笑容
That's what I would do if l were you.
如果我像你，就会哇做
But I'm not, so you do it.
但我唔像，所以你要做
OK.
好哎
What?
吓?
That was beautiful.
真你好感人
Anyways, where were we?
你喇，我吡讲到冰 ?
I'm "huge"?
大和焦，…-
Surprised to see me, Makunga?
见到我好奇哩，猛管家 ?
Well, I'm here to set things straight, like a real lion!
我像得有登喝你讨回公道 狮子气慨呀 !
Is this real enough for you? How about this? This is for setting me up!
哇锡狮子气慨未 ? 哇又点呀?呢拳报复你陷害我 !
This is for stealing my dad's job! This is for humiliating my family!
呢拳报复你抢吐我阿苞份工! 呢拳报复你侮辱我屋企 !
And making me look like a fool!
仲搞到我成个傻仔叶 !
Had enough? Sure, fly away!
顶唔顺呀?好吃，屎走咱 !
Coward.
魔此
The water. It's gone.
水源，方吐啦 !
It's never gone dry before.
个水漂从来未试过方水
- We'll need a lot more dying holes. - How could this happen?
我哟要据多化个谭等死鞠 点解会哇 ?
Out of my way! What is going on here?!
咪阻住我 ! 发生世喇事?
The watering hole is dry! There's barely water for one of us!
个水潭有了晒水 ! 泽返听水最多锡一焦动物侯咋
- Good observation, Shirley. - I'm Bobby.
你真像好眼，莎莉 ! 我叫波比
Makunga, what do we do?
猛管家，而家加算 ?
Quiet!
静哟 !
Listen up! I'm afraid there is only one solution to this horrible crisis:
聘清楚 ! 面对呢炊可怕啤危机 我号只有一个办法就像…
Weill all have to fight for it.
打大交事水饮
- We can't fight for it. - That's crazy.
唔可以打大交架 简直乱史
That's not fair. You'd win!
哇唔公平，你赢梗哎 !
Exactly, Shirley.
知就好啦，水痢!
I'm Bob...
我叫波比…
Sorry, folks, but life isn't fair. I'm in charge now,
对唔住，生命像唔公平嘎 ! 而家呢度我话事
thanks to Alakay, the dancing lion.
多得咽焦跳舞狮子亚拉奇
Please, Makunga, this is the only water on the reserve.
求吓你咱，猛管家 保护区入面得呢个水源咋
If you're thirsty, you'll have to look for water off the reserve.
也你口渴叭 你味出去保护区外面揭水唾
- Off the reserve? - It's too dangerous!
保护区外面? 太龟险喇 !
Hunters would shoot us!
出面哇多猎人 ! 哇咪即你自届 !
No one leaves the reserve and survives!
方动物克开保护区 可以返到哮 !
I left the reserve!
我礁开遇保访区 !
And survived.
我仲返到听
Il can do something about this.
我可以去搞扩呢音喇
Looks like a clogged pipe, like we get in New York. I'll travel upriver...
可能你水管塞注 呢哟事弓约大把啦，我去上游…
- Upriver? - Off the reserve?
上游? 谁开保护区 ?
You?
还你 ?
Yeah. I'll unclog the pipe and bring back your water.
像还我，我会通亚人条水管 带水番噬 !
Great! I'd help you pack, but by the looks of that hat, 1 see you're all set!
好 ! 我旭你执行李，顶眉都戴住 我论你都行得喇 !
Fine. Go ahead, laugh. Laugh your mane off. I'll prove you wrong.
好，笑啦，笑甩晒你哟毛喇 我会证明你你错听
Maybe you should try a little rain dance.
我话你不如跳求十舞好遇
Zuba would know what to do.
狂爸应该有办法噬
- Where's Zuba? - You don't care about us.
狂爸喉末呀? 伍完全唔顾我吨
Zuba should be in charge, not you.
应该由狮爸话事，而唔你你 !
All right, fine!
好哎 1好!
As an added measure, I will consult with Zuba!
我就顺应民意 走去证询吓狮笃 !
Marty?
马提?
Hey! Marty!
喂!马提!
Where'd you get the fruity hat?
顶帽好喝，喉站度买架 ?
Excuse me! Excuse me!
唔好意思 ! 唔好意思 !
Hi. Is Marty in there?
咀，马提吃咪度 ?
Anyone seen Marty?
下个见明马提?
Which one of us is Marty?
焉个你马提?
All right. Well, if you see him,
好哎，见到伍吸话
tell him his friend Alex came to say goodbye.
就话伍朋友亚力同伍讲拜拜啦 !
Goodbye? Don't go. Where are you going?
拜拜?咪走呀，你去下呀?
- Can we come? - No. I have to do this alone.
一亚咱 ? 唔得，呢件事要由我自己去做
You can't leave the reserve!
你唔可以克开保护区 !
What are you doing?
你做昱呀?
- They'll get your hat. - Hunters are everywhere!
伍吡会揭到你项由 出面四国都你猿人 !
Could you leave the hat?
留低顶由得嘛 ?
Marty! 1 know you're in there.
马提各住 ! 我知你吃度
Before I go, 1 got something I want to say.
喉我走之前，我有样喇同你讲
You've been a great friend.
你像一个好好只朋友
You've helped me so often to see the bright side of my problems
每炎我烦恪吸时候 你鲍像会帮我暗到好吃一面
that I never think of you having any.
所以我方诠过你都会有烦属
l wasn't there for you when you needed me.
你需要我啤时候我有理你
Just like back at the zoo.
好似动物园咽午哇
What kind of friend does that make me? A pretty lousy friend, I guess.
我算你世喇朋友 ? 我你个好差吸损友
I just want you to know that I...
我泽你想话你知你真像…
You're one in a million.
蕊中么一吸 !
This is touching.
真你好感人呀
So could you turn around so l can tell you to your face?
哇你而家可唔可以塌通身 等我当面对住你讲呀 ?
That's right. Gotcha!
方错鄙，中呀!
l see you in there! Yeah, you.
我见到你喇 ! 你呀，你呀!
You, right there.
你，喉咽度 !
Twelfth row, two hundred and third from the left.
第十二行 左下数起第二百零三焦
That's you, Marty.
就像你喇，马提 !
I know it's you.
我认得你
Know what makes you special?
你知唔知你有畔特别 ?
These guys are white with black stripes. You're black with white stripes.
伍吡个个都你白底黑于 得你像黑底白间咱
You're a dreamer, Marty.
你像一个欧想家，马提
Always have been. You have great taste in music
你不骂都像 你对音乐好有品味
and horrible taste in friends.
但你后朋友就方世眼光
Well, not Melman and Gloria, but me.
唔你话遂文同歌莉亚，像话我
OK, I'm in.
好啦，预埋我
Marty, you can't come with me.
马提，你唔可以跟埋史
You don't have a choice.
我唔认钨你有得后
- People are out there! - You're crazy! Come back!
出面四转都你人 你吡癫吐叭 ! 返噬呀!
The people will get you!
人类肯定会灯死你 !
Don't lose the hat!
咪源注你顶避呀 !
Bye, hat!
拜拜，贝!
Any water?
有方水呀?
No, just more diamonds and gold.
方呀，掘极都你镜石同黄金
Don't give up hope.
唔好放束
Listen up! I will help you!
职住呀 ! 等我帮你吡 !
There's only one way to get your precious water.
只有一个地方 可以得到珍贵听食水
I, your beloved King Julien
我…你哟数党呈朱利安国王
must simply make a small sacrifice to my good friends, the water gods,
要将一份神桂啤困品 送界我咽位好朋友水之神替
in the volcano!
伍就喉火山度 !
What does that do?
哇有叭用呢 ?
What does that do? Excellent question.
啦有叭用?加得真你好
My sacrifice goes in the volcano.
我咕呢份祭品 只要一藩咏去火山之和后
The friendly gods eat up my sacrifice.
咽位友善啤神霆 就会食咏咽件条品
"Thank you for the sacrifice."
「 好好味，多谢你件轩品1
"Here, have another." "No, I've had enough."
「叶呀，食多件妹品啦] 「唔使，我今日食饮吐啦]
"I'll be insulted unless you have another."
「 你食多件啦 如果唔你我会唔开心]
"] don't want another sacrifice!"
「 我哑想再食多件呀! 1
"Look at you! You're skinny!" "No! I've had enough!"
「 上吓你 ! 你哇鬼瘦 1 1 「唔啦 ! 我话我食鸳喇 ! 1
The gods eat the sacrifice. They are grateful.
神替食咏件妹品之和后 自然会感激
They give me some water, and then I give it to you.
然后送哟水界我 我就会带界你吡
What?
畔话 ?
Does it work?
像咪得架 ?
No! I mean, yes.
唔你 ! 我像族你
Well, Maurice?
咀，莫利斯?
Ah, it's fifty-fifty.
一半一半吨
Weill do it!
博一博啦!
Excellent!
好极 !
Now all l need is someone who would like to go into the volcano
而家只要喉我号当中 揭焦动物肯跳落火山度
and get eaten by gods.
界神震食就得哮
Any hands! Hands, anybody!
淮手哎 ! 去就窜手啦 !
l need someone, perhaps who has never found love,
胺位你可能从未得到明爱
who could look death straight in the eyeball. A real, genuine hero.
伍可以扰恨正视死神 做一个真正听英雄
- I'll do it. - Melman?
等我去啦 ! 遵文 ?
Hurry up! Before we all come to our senses!
快哟啦 ! 趁我吨未回复理智 !
Melman, what is wrong with you?
递文，你点解要哇做 ?
I'm dying anyway. If there's a chance it'll get you water, it's worth it.
我像咪都会死，如果我米粕 可以令你有水饮，嘲都算值得咱
Are you nuts?
你冲吐叭 ?
l want you to know, back at the zoo,
歌莉亚，我想话界你知 喉动物园入面
it was never the doctors or prescriptions that kept me going.
其实唔像哟医生同埋哟药 令我可以继续生存
It was always you.
而像全奔你
Seeing you every day.
只要每一日都见到你
That's what kept me going.
就令到我有生存吸力量
Melman! Wait!
遵文 ! 等阵 !
Melman! Melman! Melman!
邀文 ! 六文 ! 遵文 !
You going to mope like this all day?
你打算成日都喉度发霉呀?
Don't "hmph" me.
唔好哼我1
Listen, Zuba. A miracle happened.
匠住，狮区 难得有言踊
Our son came back to us. How come that is not good enough for you?
令我吨个仔返普噬我吨身巡 你做叭仲嫌三嫌四?
What are you saying, woman?
你喉度喻蕊喇呀，女人?
We lost him once, Zuba. Let's not lose him again.
我吨失去咏伍一葡 唔好再失去多炊
Zubal
狮区 !
- Zuba! - Get out of here!
快哟走开 !
What do you want?
你想点呀?
It's awful.
今洪羔啦 !
The watering hole is dried up.
水潭扰端端方晒水
Dried up? That's impossible!
有了晒水? 根本有可能 !
There's nothing left!
而家世都及啦 !
You're alpha lion, Makunga. What are you gonna do about it?
你像狂族特首，猛管家 哇咪由你搞普扩伍唾
Your son, Alakay, he said he could fix it. He's gone upriver.
你个仔垩拉和奇话伍会搞拓 伍去吐上游呀
- Off the reserve?! - No!
保护区外面? 头啦 !
I tried to stop him. I told him it was suicide.
我试遇阻止伍 我话哇做等於自规
He was determined to prove himself to you.
但你伍话要威界你暗 死都要哇做
You stay here, in case he comes back!
你喉呢度等 伍或者会走返荔噬 !
Hurry, Zuba!
快哟啦，狮葡 !
I'm so parched.
好鬼口喝添 !
Is this place starting to freak you out?
呢搓地方越行越除森 ?
Weill slip in, find the problem. Hunters will never know we were here.
我吡史哆声搞扩个问题 猎人就唔会发党我号噬明
Why are we doing this?
其实点解我呈要哇样做呢 ?
Maybe my dad will think I'm...
我从号可能会觉得我…
l want to show him I'm a real lion.
名之我想伍当我像售真狮子啦
As opposed to a chocolate lion.
喇通你像焦朱十力狮子哗
I know this may sound hard to believe, but apparently, lions don't dance.
我知道匠落准以置信 但你原来狮子像唔跳磊台
What?!
吓?
As far as my dad is concerned.
至少对我和釜吨喀讲你哇
As far as people are concerned, you're a hit.
但像对哟人类史讲 你就像大明星
In New York. This is Africa... much tougher crowd.
咽度你经约，呢度像非洲 呢度哟观办闭兴哟
Marty, this is it!
马提，揭到喇 !
This is the clog! Come on.
就你呢度 ! 噬啦
Well, there's the water.
喂，哟水味喉度噬
Stay down. Look at that.
伏低 ! 你蝉吓!
Knit one, purl two.
高针，低人针
It's her.
像伍呀!
- Is this right? - Very good.
哇喘唔吵呀 ? 做得好
Nana, slow down.
娘娘，慢哟啦
You're a little tangled, aren't you?
你有哟混乱，像咪 ?
No, don't pull. I'll do it.
咪呀，咪拉呀，等我嗓
We need dynamite. Got any?
要有炸药先扩，你有方炸药?
Oh, snap! I just used my last stick this morning!
噢，惨啦 ! 最和后一袋我今朝都用埋 !
- Savages! - Evasive maneuvers!
野釜人呀! 走得快，好世界 !
- Serpentine, serpentine! - Squiggly squid maneuver!
走得摩，方鼻哥 ! 鲈鳃游得中 !
Zag, zig-zag, zig ziggy zag!
闪呀! 闪闪缩! 内内缩缩!
No, no! Squiggly squid!
唔好呀 ! 鲍鳃游得中 !
Etch A Sketch!
伍虹我哑到 !
That's too complex! Octopus, octopus!
情况好堪广 ! 八不急 ! 八下熏 !
- Run, Marty! - l can't leave you here!
走呀，双提 ! 我点可以掉低你 !
Go get help! Squiggly squid maneuver! Go! Go! Squiggly squid!
去求救啦 ! 学就急游得估一大 ! 走呀 ! 走呀 ! 就急游得让 !
Etch A Sketch! Etch A Sketch!
伍频我哑到 ! 伍频我哑到 !
Save us We love you
救我吨 我呈党你
OK.
得听
OK, OK, OK.
得上 9 得上 9 得肯…
- Save us - Melman
救我吨 遵文
- We love you
我呈党你
Save us
救我吨
OK, here we go. OK, OK.
得啤，死就死啦 !
- Melman - We love you
遵文 我呈党你
- Save us
救我吨
Here we go! Here we go!
死就死啦 ! 死就死啦 !
- What's all the hoopla about? - Joe?
做昱哇大障仗 ? 阿祖 ?
Joe the Witch Doctor? We thought you were dead!
和巫医阿祖先生 ? 仲以为你死咏添 !
So did I. Then I realized I'm covered in brown spots.
我都以为，但像和后尾发现 我成身都有斑点
So Melman's not dying!
即你遵文都唔会死 !
- Melman's not dying! - Oh, no!
遵文唔会死 ! 噢，葬啤 !
Melman!
邀文 !
Move!
唔该借借 !
Don't do this! Julien, stop this! This is crazy!
唔好呀 ! 朱利安 停手呀 ! 你疯吐呼 !
Oh, suddenly throwing a giraffe into a volcano to make water is crazy!
喂!突然间将焦长栖鹿 掉落火山口去求神赐水算你疯 !
Yes!
像呀 !
- Please, Melman! Stop! - Gloria?
求吓你，咀文 ! 唔好呀! 歌莉亚?
- You can't do this! - Why not?
你唔好哇做 ! 点解呀?
You can't do this, Melman.
你唔好哇做，尼文 !
First, that hurts.
我想话伯你匠我好痛!
Second, I've only got 18 hours to live, anyway.
我仲想访，其实我条命 只你泽炙十八个尔咋
Melman, I gotta know...
遵文，我要搞清楚…
...did you mean those things you said about me?
头先你对我讲顺喇你味真心架 ?
Of course I did.
当然像真心
- That's crazy. - Itis?
真你傻 你叭 ?
It's crazy to think I had to go halfway around the world...
像我余，傻到居然以为 要去地球啤另一遵先揭到爱…
...to find out the perfect guy for me
原来我一直等紧上真命天子…
lived right next door.
早就住吃隔得
Then it's you and me, neighbor.
你噶你陪住我啦，那居
You and me for the next 18 hours.
你同我过埋咽十八个鳃
I'll take whatever you got.
我会一直隘住你
- Maurice, what happened? - l believe the fat lady has sung.
英利斯，点解会哇 ? 伍等到有都长至有今日
- What's going on here? - Marty!
呢度发生只事? 马提 !
Alex is in big trouble! We got to get upriver fast!
亚力今炎大件事喇 ! 我吨要即刻超去上游 !
- What about the plane? - Perfect! Come on!
不如用飞机 正到闻 ! 行啦 !
The plane won't be fixed until the suits meet our demands.
如果您班西装友 唔答应界产假我员嘱话
Now, maternity leave.
我吨就唔会复工
Maternity leave? You're all males.
要产假做昱 ? 你吡像男性喝 !
We need that plane for a rescue mission.
我哟要架示机唉等住救命
There's nothing I can do until we bust up this union.
我都及符 除非可以搞扩个工会啦
I'll bust up all of you if you don't get this plane going.
如果你吡仲唔吻啤声整郝架机 我就搞扩晒你
Can't you see these commies have my hands tied? No maternity leave.
呢班土共搞到我钱手钱脚 唔会有产假 !
Maybe a certain someone wouldn't want these blowing around on the savanna.
如果亚相吃呢个热带雨林传开去 唔像哇好听 ?
All right. You get your maternity leave.
好喇 ! 界产假你哟得未?
Finally.
扩喇
Where we headed? What's going on? Where are we going?
我吡去韶呀? 发生只事 ? 我吨去紧下 ?
Oh, no! Please! Don't put me there! No!
咀，唔好呀! 你吡唔好放我吃度 ! 唔好呀!
This is wrong.
哇你错听
You see? You are survivors.
见到啦 ? 你吡像生还者 !
Now, how about a nice lion casserole?
不如整理个「红烧狂子头」 叶 !
You can't eat a lion.
狮子点食得架
Don't worry, it tastes like chicken.
唔使奖，同共肉盖喇多
No, no, no. Don't listen to her.
停呀，停呀，唔好凤伍讲
She's out of her mind, people!
伍发神经架，唔好呀 !
I'm from New York City!
我喷自纽约市 !
It's me, Alex the lion! From Central Park!
你我呀 ! 狮子亚力 ! 中央公园响焦呢 !
Dad!
签哪 !
What were you thinking, son? You got no business being out here!
你究竟论紧世喇呀仔 ? 你喉度可以做到哟也喇呀 !
Stay behind me.
匿喉我咕和后面 !
They're New Yorkers. They're just rude and frightened people.
伍史纽约人 伍吡只你粗鲁同细脸呀人类
Stay back!
退后呀 !
You'd let your dinner get away?
你吡由得晚餐走咏去?
- What are you doing? - The only thing 1 know how to do.
你想做世喇呀仔 ? 梗像做我唯一识做啤喇啦
What the heck?
做世喇呀伍 ?
Hey, I know those moves.
喂 9 呢北招咪像…
Alex?
亚力?
- It's Alex the lion! - From Central Park!
像狮子亚力呀 ! 中央公园咽焦 !
It is Alex!
像垩力呀!
Only one lion can move like that!
只有一焦狂子识得哇榜跳舞 !
He's beautiful.
伍好型呀 !
I can't believe it.
真你难以置信
How does he do that?
伍你点做到架 ?
What are you doing?
你做昱呀?
I'm dancing with my son! I think.
诊住禾我个得仔跳三 !
Don't think, Dad. Feel!
唔好认，用feel !
Butterfly!
蝴蝶飞 !
I'm feeling it! I'm feeling it!
我feel到啦 ! 我feel到啦 !
Roar!
只 !
That was beautiful. Now let's eat!
你效有型吸，但你我哟要开餐 !
Dad, look out!
签吨，虹住呀 !
What the...
搞叭呀…
Alex! Get in!
亚力 ! 上吧啦!
She's got a gun! Get out while we can!
伍有枝检 ! 再喉度就危险喇 !
- What? - She's got a gun!
畔话 ? 伍有枝检 !
Get out while we can! Pass it on!
再喉度就危险喇 ! 传并去啦 !
He said let's have some fun and take out the dam. Basset hound.
伍话要去开心咱 要搞扩座堤填
Skipper! Alex wants to take out the dam.
队长 ! 亚力话要搞扩座堤南
All right! But it's his funeral.
好啦 ! 但你伍死梗架喝
- Hard to port! - Aye-aye, Skippy!
塌左啦 ! 知道，队长 !
Bring it on! Bring it on!
我噬喇 ! 我噬喇 !
Come back! That's my dinner!
返虽呀 ! 我咯晚餐 !
Kowalski, full throttle.
高革斯基，要出招喇 !
Music!
音乐 !
- l like this song. - It never gets old.
我镍意呢首歌呀
It does have a catchy hook. Come about! Bring her in low!
又好匠又易上口 ! 掉头啦 ! 向下生 !
Hold onto your skirts! It's dam-busting time!
某实你吨休裙 ! 要搞扩座堤填 !
Hold on tight, baby! Here we go!
捉实呀，裤上贝 ! 我呈去啦 !
Tell them no! Pull up! They'll kill us!
叫伍吨唔好呀 ! 想升 ! 想贡死我吡叭 !
There's got to be another way! Pass it on!
肯定会有其他办法 ! 传开去啦 !
They say no pull up. Kill us. There's no other way. Basset hound.
伍话「唔好疏升1 「杀死我呈上 [有其他办法」
Are you sure?
唔像呀嘛 ?
Men, there is no sacrifice greater than someone else's.
老友 ! 最伟大啤物牲 醒你粕竹其他动物啦 !
No! Medic!
惨呀 ! 军医 !
Ramming speed!
全速撞贡 !
Bring it on!
即管喀啦 !
Bad kitties.
旨…旨…猎!
I don't know why the sacrifice didn't work.
点解奉筷轩品竟然会失败 ?
The science seemed so solid.
哇做完全会手科学
I'd jump right in that volcano if l wasn't so good at whistling.
如果我唔像吹口哨噶号 我都即刻跳落去呀 !
It's you! I found you!
像你啦 ! 揭到你啦 !
Mort?
毛毛 ?
Bad fishy!
慢强和急 上
l wonder if the gods like seafood.
唔知哟神震鳃哑镍意海鲜呢
Let's find out.
去确认吓
Look, Maurice.
蝉吓，莫利斯
- That was quick. - I did it!
即刻见效 全靠我咋 !
I did it! I did it!
全计我咋 ! 全壮我咋 !
OK, you did it!
你，你靠你 !
Oh, yes!!
好喇呀 !
Look!
暗吓!
- It's Alakay! - It's Zuba!
像垩拉奇呀! 像狮爷呀!
You did it!
全计你号 !
Alakay, Zuba, you did it!
犹爸，亚拉奇，全靠你吨 !
Zuba! Alakay!
狮区 ! 垩拉麻 !
You're back!
你吡返噬喇 !
I'm so glad you're safe!
你吡有事 ! 真你好呀
Out of my way.
咪阻住我 !
Well, well, well.
咀，喂，喂!
You know, Zuba, if ! remember correctly, you quit the pride.
点桂呀，狮笃，如果我及记错 你属咏战喇喝
And you were kicked out.
而你就佬我放逐咏
So don't think that this changes anything.
所以千神唔好以入 哇就可以[撕水重来]
You're right. In fact, we humbly present you with this token of appreciation.
你喘吸 ! 其实，我喇只不明 你想献上呢份礼物界你哮
Aman bag. Very popular where I’m from.
像男装手袋 ! 我住咽度好检架 !
- Don't know what to say. - Still be tough and carry your stuff.
我唔知请畔好添 你可以用嗓装呀，级续扮喇
Does the strap adjust? This will go very nicely for me when I go out hiking.
休种可以较吗 ? 个袋袍晒我 好喘我行山咽阵用
But you're still banished.
不过你都促像放逐吃
We figured you'd say that.
预咏你会哇讲啦
My handbag!
我个手袋 !
You bad kitty!
你焦训和猫 !
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
唔好唔好…停呀停呀停呀 !
You deserve this, son.
你应得咕，乖仔 !
Welcome to the pride.
接受莹只听 !
Thanks, Dad. But this belongs to you.
多府黎喇，但你伍像属於你咯
No, son. To us!
错，你属兴我吨先至喀 !
My son! The King of New York!
我咱乖仔 ! 你纽约市之王 !
That's my baby!
像我肯冬仔 !
Love transcends all differences.
真爱你可以克服差县
We are gathered here today to celebrate such a love.
今日我员票集喉度 就你要庆祝呢种爱
Do you take each other, for better or for worse?
你顾意不论褐福 永踪都相爱虽?
For better, please.
像福就至好啦 !
What a beautiful, weird couple!
好一对美富咕骑呢新人 !
That's not going to last.
我诊唔会长久 !
Can I kiss the bride?
可以界我锡新娘吗，队长?
No! Music!
唔得 ! 音乐 !
- Struts. - Check.
支架 好
- Flaps!
机翼!
- Diamonds and gold. - Check.
氏石同黄金 好
- Bye-bye! - We'll miss you!
拜拜 ! 我吡会措住你哟 !
See you later!
和后会有期 !
Weill be back after the honeymoon in Monte Carlo,
我吨吃蒙地卡淖度完蜜月
or whenever the gold runs out.
或者使旺哟黄金就会返嗓
Come back soon!
快哟返呀!
Mom, let them take their time. New York isn't going anywhere, right, guys?
咪哇啦婧味，由得伍吨啦 弓约又唔会走咱，你味呀老友 ?
You're right about that!
你呀，讲得史 !
As long as I'm with her...
只要同伍喉理一首…
..and you two, I don't care where we are.
仲有同埋你雨个 哇就吃尊都唔紧要
She has the most amazing laugh.
伍吸笑声真你最爽朗 !
Love has no boundaries!
党你么疆界噬 !
Looks like you're stuck with us for a while.
瞳喀你要医住我号多段时间喇
Dad? What's wrong?
签吨?做畔呀你?
I just thought we could hang out a bit and...
我仲以为我吨可以去蒲吓添…
- You got me! - l got you, son!
你玩我 ! 整屯你咱，仔 !
You got me with my thing. You brought it back around on me.
界你玩到添，你学吃我 你模仿我只整屯我
I got you, son!
玩咏你啦，仔!
The old man's not too bad, eh, Marty?
我老豆唔错呀，你咪呀马提?
- Marty? Who's Marty? - Come on.
马提?站个马提呀? 算吧啦你!
- [don't know no Marty. - You can't fool me.
我唔知旭个马提喝 ! 你呢我唔到上 !
Ain't no Marty here.
呢度方亏提喝
Marty! I can look into your eyes, and I know it's you.
马提 ! 只要我一望你对了眼 我就知道咽个你你啦
Hey! Shake the hot things! Shake the hot things!
喂 ! 热情阁气! 热情交撮 !
Shake 'em! Shake 'em! Shake ‘em!
欣气 ! 欣气1!拉气!